<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Guide on Utkarsh M</title><link>https://utkar5hm.github.io/categories/guide/</link><description>Recent content in Guide on Utkarsh M</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://utkar5hm.github.io/categories/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Adding Hotstpot/AP mode support for MT7921 on Linux (stock / linux-g14 kernel)</title><link>https://utkar5hm.github.io/posts/hotspot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://utkar5hm.github.io/posts/hotspot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since the current Linux kernel drivers for MT7921 doesn’t support Monitor mode, I couldn’t enable the wifi hotspot through my Zephyrus G14 on Linux. So I found out that there is a patch available for the drivers which might come out on later Linux kernel releases. If you want, you can wait for the time being or try compiling the kernel with the patch by yourselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will be showing you on how to apply the patch over both the stock and linux-g14 kernel. I’m using Arch Linux on Zephyrus-G14 GA401QH. applying the patch on stock firmware should most probably work for other laptops with MT7921 and could be performed similarly for other distros.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting started with Migen | A python based HDL</title><link>https://utkar5hm.github.io/posts/migen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://utkar5hm.github.io/posts/migen/</guid><description>&lt;p>In digital design, the complexity of designing a circuit gave birth to standard languages to describe digital circuits (i.e. Hardware Description Languages - HDL). HDLs are used to model hardware elements very concurrently. Verilog HDL and VHDL are the most popular HDLs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digital circuits are described at Registers Transfer Level (RTL) using HDL. Then logic synthesis tool will generate details of gates and interconnection to implement courses. This synthesized result can be used for fabrication by having placement and routing components, and later its functionality can be verified using simulation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reducing cpu Usage in Windows | Guide</title><link>https://utkar5hm.github.io/posts/reducing-cpu-usage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://utkar5hm.github.io/posts/reducing-cpu-usage/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you frustrated by high CPU usage on your Windows PC? Do you want to speed up your system performance and save battery life or just play CPU intensive games? If so, this post is for you.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>These are some tips and tricks that I’ve learned from various sources like &lt;a href="https://libreddit.spike.codes/r/Battlefield/comments/57nh6y/bf1_performance_tips_for_pc_potentially_huge_fps/">reddit&lt;/a> on how to reduce CPU usage in Windows over the years running the weaklings i3-3210 and i5-2500. These are some of the things that worked for me and I hope they will help you too. This is from one of my older threads that I made for nitksf.tech.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>